Payman Abbasian

Zirkelstraße 4, 45143 Essen, Germany

M +46 76 325 3939 M +49 176 206 44944

info@pabbasian.com

Profile

I am a full stack app/web developer. I am working in the technology field since 2005 with my primary focus on asp.net stack, however this changed over the past few years with the rise of javascript frameworks, node and other new kids in the block. I find myself spending more time nowadays on a terminal window than visual studio and when it comes to databases I am moving my stuff to postgresql.

Skills

N-tier Applications and Microsoft DNA Structure (Web-based, Intranet, Client/Server, Web-Service) with Over a decade of freelance web development experience developed dozens of web portals, shops, galleries and five years of advanced JavaScript experience.

Java, C#, asp (.net, mvc), php, MsSQL, PostgreSql, nHibernate, EF, XML Web Services, Com/DCom/Com+ , DHTML , JavaScript (node, angular, meteor, knockout, jquery), CSS, XHTML

Certification

Microsoft Certified Solution Developer (MCSD) 2002-2004

Education

Environmental Helth, Azad University, Birjand 200-2002

Experience

SCADA developer, IBH Systems (e.on ECT); Essen, Germany – 2017-ongoing Java, eclipse SCADA, IOT, Industrial gateways (Modbus, Profibus, IEC104)

Software developer, Violer; , Sweden – 2016-2017 node-js, Meteor-js, mongo-db

System utvecklare, Jetsoft; Boras, Sweden - 2015-2015

I was responsible of making an interactive dashboard for an ERP system using angular on front and nancyFX on the back plus a variety of customisable widgets for analysing data (charts, heat-maps, pivot grids)

System utvecklare, Getupdated; Boras, Sweden – 2011-2015

- -developing a modular report system which could be customised based on client needs.
- -gathering and analysing data from different sources and apis (google ads, analytics, etc)
- -development of internal web portals and client portals
- -Microsoft crm development and integration with internal portals
- -developing tools to help seo technicians analyse a website and make an offer to client

Software developer, Chargoon; Tehran, Iran – 2009-2010

Migrated a large scale classic asp.net application into an ajax based app along side working on development on UI/UX and a bunch .net user controls such as a lazy-loaded searchable treeview, gridviews, etc using YUI and jquery.

Software developer, Poortan; Tehran, Iran – 2007-2009

I developed a windows based client/server CRM application for a major telemarketing company on top panasonic PBX boxes using .net and Mssql.